♪
( Alice murmuring )
( chain rattles )
( Kirito panting )
Alice: KIRITO.
DID YOU CARRY ME
ALL THE WAY UP HERE?
Kirito: DAMN RIGHT, I DID,
AND IT WASN’T EASY.
MAYBE A "THANK YOU" OR A--
( gasps ) WH-WHAT’RE YOU DOING?
( Alice gasps ) HOW DISGUSTING.
YOU’RE COMPLETELY
DRENCHED IN SWEAT!
AND YOU HAVE STAINED
MY GARMENTS!
HOW DARE YOU FOUL THEM UP?!
Kirito: ARE YOU KIDDING?!
( grunts ) OW!
( singing in Japanese )
( chain clanking )
( Kirito groans )
( patting )
Alice: WHERE IS YOUR PARTNER?
Kirito: HEY, HIS NAME’S EUGEO.
Alice: FINE, EUGEO.
HE IS NOT HERE.
FROM THE CLOUDTOP GARDEN,
THERE IS A STAIRWAY LEADING UP.
BEFORE REACHING
THIS FLOOR, HOWEVER,
HE WOULD HAVE HAD TO FACE
OUR STRONGEST KNIGHT.
Kirito: YEAH?
AND WHO WOULD THAT BE?
Alice: UNCLE.
OR, RATHER, COMMANDER BERCOULI.
( Kirito gasps )
OH, MAN. NOW WHAT?
( sighs )
♪
I KNOW.
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE UMBRA ELEMENT.
ADHERE POSSESSION.
OBJECT I.D. WLSS703.
DISCHARGE.
Alice: WHAT ARE YOU
DOING THAT FOR?
Kirito: I’M TRYING TO FIND
WHERE THE BLUE ROSE SWORD’S AT.
IF I CAN FIND IT,
I’M GONNA FIND HIM.
HE’S UNDER US.
- Alice: ONE MOMENT.
- Kirito: EH?
Alice: YOU DID THIS, I TAKE IT?
Kirito: YEAH.
I MANAGED TO STOP THE BLEEDING,
BUT MY SACRED ARTS
CAN ONLY DO SO MUCH.
DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN HEAL YOUR EYE YOURSELF?
Alice: NOT NOW. THERE IS NOT
ENOUGH SACRED POWER IN THE AIR.
I CANNOT REPAIR IT
UNTIL SOLUS HAS RISEN.
I AM STILL FEELING SOME PAIN,
AND DEPTH PERCEPTION
WILL BE AN ISSUE,
BUT NEITHER
WILL KEEP ME FROM FIGHTING.
Kirito: A-ARE YOU SURE?
Alice: YES.
I WISH TO FEEL THIS PAIN.
IT IS THE PROOF OF MY RESOLVE
TO FIGHT THE CHURCH.
I AM FINE.
Kirito: OKAY.
I GET IT.
AND, IF WE’RE EVER IN BATTLE,
I’LL MAKE SURE
TO PROTECT YOUR RIGHT.
( chuckles )
( ice crunching underfoot )
Alice: IS EUGEO
THE ONE RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS?
Kirito: I’M PRETTY SURE
IT WAS HIM. I MEAN...
REMEMBER HOW HE ACTIVATED
PERFECT CONTROL ON US BEFORE?
TO BE HONEST, I DIDN’T THINK
IT WAS THIS POWERFUL.
( Alice gasps )
- IT CAN’T BE.
- Kirito: HUH?
Alice: UNCLE!
Kirito: WHAT THE...
♪
Alice: UNCLE.
Kirito: NO WAY.
EUGEO DIDN’T DO THAT TO HIM.
( Alice sniffs ) HE DID NOT,
BUT I HAVE AN IDEA WHO DID.
YEARS AGO, UNCLE TOLD ME
THAT PRIME SENATOR CHUDELKIN
HAD BEEN GRANTED THE AUTHORITY
TO TURN ANYONE TO STONE,
AN ART CALLED DEEP FREEZE.
Kirito: REALLY? BUT THEY’RE
SUPPOSED TO BE ON THE SAME SIDE.
WHY WOULD HE BETRAY
ONE OF HIS OWN KNIGHTS?
DOESN’T MAKE SENSE.
Alice: I THINK UNCLE
SECRETLY HARBORED DOUBTS
ABOUT THE ORDERS
ISSUED BY THE SENATE,
AND YET, LIKE MYSELF,
HE BELIEVED THERE COULD BE
NO PEACE IN THE REALM
WITHOUT THE RULE OF THE CHURCH,
SO HE CONTINUED TO PERFORM
HIS DUTIES REGARDLESS.
( sobs )
( stone creaking )
THE SENATOR MAY HAVE
ALL THE AUTHORITY, BUT THIS?
THERE IS NO REASON
TO TREAT HIM SO HORRIBLY, NONE!
UNCLE!
( crying )
( gasps )
UNCLE!
NO, YOU MUSTN’T TRY TO MOVE!
YOU’LL DESTROY YOURSELF!
STOP IT!
( Bercouli sighs )
HEY, LITTLE GIRL.
WHY DON’T YOU
CUT OUT THAT CRYIN’?
A SMILE SUITS YOU BETTER.
( Alice gasps ) UNCLE.
Bercouli: LOOK AT YOU.
I GUESS YOU MADE IT
OVER THAT WALL, KIDDO.
FOR 300 YEARS, I TRIED
AND COULDN’T BREAK THE SEAL,
BUT YOU DID.
Alice: WHAT DO I DO?
I CAN’T JUST LEAVE YOU HERE.
Bercouli:
DON’T YOU FUSS OVER ME.
I’M HAPPY FOR YOU.
YOU’RE STRONGER THAN EVER.
THERE’S NOTHING LEFT
FOR ME TO TEACH YOU.
Alice: WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THAT IS NOT TRUE!
THERE IS STILL MUCH
I NEED TO LEARN FROM YOU!
Bercouli: YOU KNOW ALL YOU NEED.
IF ANYONE CAN GUIDE THIS WORLD
TO WHERE IT OUGHT TO BE,
IT’S YOU.
HEYA, PUNK.
LOOK AFTER HER FOR ME.
( Kirito grunts )
YOU GOT IT.
( stone cracking )
( Bercouli chuckles )
YOU WANNA FIND YOUR PARTNER.
PRIME SENATOR CHUDELKIN,
HE TOOK HIM.
( Kirito gasps )
Bercouli: HEADING
TO THE PONTIFEX’S CHAMBER.
HURRY, BEFORE THE KID
GETS TRAPPED
IN THE MAZE OF HIS MEMORIES.
( Alice gasps )
THANK YOU, UNCLE.
( tone chimes )
Kirito: HUH?
NO WAY.
( grunts )
- ( tone chimes )
- ( Alice gasps )
♪
SOME HAVE TRIED
TO WIELD TWO SWORDS BEFORE,
MOSTLY PRETENTIOUS UPPER-CLASS
NOBLEMEN LOOKING TO IMPRESS.
YOU, ODDLY ENOUGH,
SEEM RATHER IMPOSING.
( Kirito gasps )
OH, YOU THINK?
I CAN’T IMAGINE FIGHTING
WITH TWO SWORDS, THOUGH.
THAT’D BE CRAZY.
Alice: ALL RIGHT.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS, WE MUST ASSUME
THE PONTIFEX HAS EUGEO BY NOW.
WHEN SHE SPEAKS,
ONE CANNOT RESIST.
HER WORDS ARE A WEB
WHICH ENTANGLE THE MIND.
Kirito:
LIKE SOME KIND OF HYPNOTIST.
YOU TALK TO HER BEFORE?
♪
Alice: ONLY ONCE.
IT WAS SIX YEARS AGO.
I REMEMBER WAKING UP AND
THE PONTIFEX STANDING BEFORE ME.
SHE SAID SHE RULED THE HUMAN
EMPIRE ON BEHALF OF THE GODS
AND HAD SUMMONED ME
TO SERVE THEIR WILL.
HER EYES WERE LIKE MIRRORS,
SILVER AND REFLECTIVE.
I DID NOT REALIZE IT
AT THE TIME, BUT I DO NOW.
I WAS TERRIFIED OF HER,
AND I KNEW I COULD NOT DEFY HER.
I WOULD ACCEPT
EVERY WORD SHE SAID
AND SERVE HER
WITH ALL OF MY BEING.
THE FEAR WAS ABSOLUTE.
IT COMPELLED ME TO OBEY,
AND, LIKE A COWARD, I DID.
Kirito: ALICE.
( Alice sighs )
NOT TO WORRY.
I KNOW WHAT I MUST DO NOW.
FOR THE SAKE OF MY SISTER
LIVING IN THE NORTH,
FOR MY FAMILY AND THE CITIZENS
OF THIS REALM,
I WILL DO
WHAT I BELIEVE IS RIGHT.
WE MUST HURRY.
TIME IS SHORT, AND WE STILL
HAVE TO REACH THE PONTIFEX.
THE PRIME SENATOR WILL TRY
TO STOP US, SO PREPARE YOURSELF.
Kirito: W-WAIT.
WHAT ABOUT THE COMMANDER?
WE CAN’T LEAVE HIM LIKE THIS.
Alice: IF WE CATCH CHUDELKIN,
WE CAN FORCE HIM
TO REVERSE THE SPELL.
OR WE CAN KILL HIM
AND SOLVE THE PROBLEM THAT WAY.
( Kirito chuckles )
- HEY.
- Alice: YES?
Kirito: YOU MENTIONED
THIS PRIME SENATOR CHUDELKIN GUY
A FEW TIMES, BUT WHAT’S THE DEAL
WITH THE OTHER SENATORS?
Alice: TO BE HONEST,
NONE OF US INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
HAVE EVER SEEN
THE OTHER SENATORS.
I KNOW THEY ARE LOCATED
ABOVE THE 96th FLOOR.
WE KNIGHTS ARE
NOT ALLOWED THERE, THOUGH.
Kirito: YOU KNOW
WHAT THESE SENATORS DO?
Alice: THEY MONITOR THE REALM.
FROM THEIR CHAMBER,
THEY OBSERVE THE WORDS AND DEEDS
OF EVERY CITIZEN
TO ENSURE THEY ARE
NOT VIOLATING THE TABOO INDEX.
WHEN SOMEONE
RUNS AFOUL OF THE TABOOS,
THEY NOTE THE VIOLATION AND
SEND A KNIGHT TO DEAL WITH IT.
Kirito: SO BASICALLY
THEY’RE PRETTY MUCH
THE EYES AND EARS
OF THE PONTIFEX.
ALTHOUGH, IF ADMINISTRATOR’S
A CONTROL FREAK,
IT’S HARD TO BELIEVE SHE’D
GIVE ANYONE THAT MUCH AUTHORITY.
IS THIS WHERE THEY ARE?
Alice: YES, IT SHOULD BE.
♪
( Kirito grunts )
( door seal hisses )
( soft chatter )
Alice: THAT IS A SACRED ART!
Kirito: DOESN’T SOUND
LIKE AN ATTACK SPELL.
Alice: ARE YOU READY?
Kirito: MM-HMM.
- ( chatter continues )
- Senator: SYSTEM CALL...
Senator 2: SYSTEM CALL...
- ( Alice gasps )
- ( Kirito gasps )
♪
- Senator 3: SYSTEM CALL...
- Senator 4: ...REBELLING INDEX.
Kirito: THEY’RE ALL JUST HEADS.
Alice: LOOK AGAIN.
THEIR BODIES
SEEM TO BE ATTACHED.
Senator 5:
DISPLAY REBELLING INDEX.
Senator 6: SYSTEM CALL.
- ( chatter continues )
- ( Kirito gasps )
THAT WAS A SENATOR?
Alice: HAVE YOU SEEN ONE BEFORE?
Kirito: YEAH,
BACK AT THE ACADEMY,
RIGHT AFTER WE FOUGHT
RAIOS AND HUMBERT.
HE APPEARED OUT OF NOWHERE.
( alarm and bell ringing )
( chatter stops )
( alarm and bell stop )
( both gasp )
♪
( senators gulping )
Senator 7: SYSTEM CALL.
- DISPLAY REBELLING INDEX.
- ( chatter resumes )
Alice: THESE MISERABLE CREATURES
ARE THE SENATORS?
WHAT A HORRIFYING FATE.
DID THE PONTIFEX DO THIS?
Kirito: YEAH, THAT’S MY BET.
THESE WERE ONCE NORMAL PEOPLE,
PROBABLY GOOD
AT THE SACRED ARTS, TOO.
SHE KIDNAPPED ’EM AND
TURNED ’EM INTO THESE THINGS.
Alice: UNFORGIVABLE.
( Chudelkin wailing )
NO! NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO!
- THIS WILL NOT DO!
- Kirito: WHO’S THAT?
( Chudelkin wails )
Alice: THE PRIME SENATOR...
CHUDELKIN.
Chudelkin:
THIS CANNOT BE HAPPENING!
( stammering )
( wailing )
THIS WON’T DO!
NO, NO, NO!
IT SIMPLY WILL NOT DO!
( yelling )
( wailing )
( gasps )
♪
( sputtering )
( gasps )
Alice: IF YOU ATTEMPT
TO INITIATE AN ART,
I WILL CUT YOUR TONGUE
RIGHT OUT OF YOUR HEAD.
( Chudelkin yelps )
THE NERVE! WAIT JUST A MOMENT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE DIED
IN THE FALL WITH THAT TRAITOR!
WHY ARE YOU ALIVE,
NUMBER THIRTY?!
Alice: I AM NOT A NUMBER!
( exhales )
MY NAME IS ALICE.
I AM NO LONGER NUMBER THIRTY.
( Chudelkin sputters )
OH.
YOU! WHY ARE YOU HERE?!
NUMBER--I MEAN, ALICE,
WHY IS YOUR SWORD
NOT EMBEDDED IN HIM?!
DON’T YOU REMEMBER?
HE’S A HERETIC,
A TRAITOR,
A PAWN OF THE DARK TERRITORY!
Alice: YOU ARE RIGHT.
HE IS A TRAITOR,
BUT HE IS NOT
FROM THE DARK TERRITORY.
THAT, I CAN ASSURE YOU.
( Chudelkin sputters ) YOU--
YOU MISERABLE KNIGHT!
YOU WISH TO BETRAY US, TOO!
WHEN I TELL YOU TO DO SOMETHING,
YOU DAMN WELL DO IT!
YOU ARE NOTHING BUT A PUPPET!
ALL YOU KNIGHTS ARE!
Alice: THE AXIOM CHURCH
TURNED US INTO PUPPETS.
( Chudelkin sputters )
Alice: YOU SEALED AWAY
OUR MEMORIES
THROUGH THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL,
FORCED US TO BE LOYAL TO YOU
AND THE CHURCH,
MADE US BELIEVE THE MYTH
THAT WE WERE KNIGHTS
SUMMONED FROM THE HEAVENS.
( Chudelkin chuckles )
YES, YOU ARE CORRECT.
I REMEMBER THE DAY WE TURNED YOU
LIKE IT WAS YESTERDAY.
YOU WERE SO YOUNG,
SO INNOCENT, SO CUTE,
BEGGING AS TEARS
STREAMED DOWN YOUR CHEEKS.
( imitating ) "PLEASE!
DON’T TAKE AWAY MY MEMORIES
OF ALL THE PEOPLE I LOVE!
DON’T MAKE ME FORGET!"
( laughing )
WHY, JUST THINKING
ABOUT IT AGAIN IS GOING
TO KEEP ME AWAKE ALL NIGHT,
LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY!
AS I RECALL,
YOU WERE BROUGHT HERE
FROM SOME BACKWATER TOWN
AND TRAINED AS AN APPRENTICE
FOR TWO YEARS.
YOU WERE SO REBELLIOUS!
ONCE, YOU SNUCK OUT
TO SEE THE MIDSUMMER FESTIVAL
LIKE A TOMBOY.
THAT SAID, YOU STUDIED HARD,
BELIEVING AGAINST ALL HOPE
THAT, ONE DAY,
YOU’D RETURN HOME AGAIN.
BUT YOU DIDN’T, AND THAT’S
BECAUSE, ONCE YOU RAISED
YOUR SYSTEM CONTROL
AUTHORITY LEVEL HIGH ENOUGH,
IT’S FORCED SYNTHESIS TIME!
YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN YOUR FACE
WHEN YOU REALIZED
YOU’D NEVER SEE YOUR HOME AGAIN.
I WANTED TO TURN YOU TO STONE
SO I COULD DISPLAY
YOUR PRECIOUS GRIEF
IN MY CHAMBER FOREVER!
- ( Alice gasps )
- ( Chudelkin laughs )
( yelps )
Alice: YOU MENTIONED
SOMETHING ODD JUST NOW.
"FORCED SYNTHESIS"?
DO YOU MEAN TO SAY
THE RITUAL CAN BE UNDERTAKEN
VOLUNTARILY AS WELL?
Chudelkin: MY, MY,
WHAT SHARP EARS YOU HAVE.
YOU’RE ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
SIX YEARS AGO, YOU WERE
SO UNBELIEVABLY STUBBORN.
YOU REFUSED TO RECITE
THE SECRET COMMANDS
FOR THE TYPICAL
SYNTHESIS RITUAL.
HONESTLY, YOU WERE THE MOST
INSUFFERABLE BRAT IMAGINABLE.
YOU GAVE ME NO CHOICE,
BUT TO DIVERT
THE AUTOMATED SENATORS
FROM THEIR NORMAL DUTIES,
THEN HAVE THEM CONDUCT A RITUAL
TO PRY THE DOOR OPEN
TO YOUR MOST PRECIOUS MEMORIES.
IT WAS A BOTHER,
BUT I SHOULDN’T COMPLAIN.
I GOT TO SEE
AN INCREDIBLE SHOW!
( laughing )
Kirito:
HE’S TALKING WAY TOO MUCH.
YEAH, LIKE HE’S STALLING.
Chudelkin: HMM.
Alice: PRIME SENATOR CHUDELKIN,
YOU HAD A LIFETIME OF AMUSEMENT
FROM MY SUFFERING.
NOW, AT THE END,
I HOPE YOU ARE SATISFIED.
( Chudelkin groaning )
Alice: I HAVE HAD ENOUGH
OF YOUR DRIVEL AND YOU.
( Chudelkin chuckles )
♪
( both gasp )
( Chudelkin laughs )
( both coughing )
YOU FOOLS! THE RITUAL
IS NOT ALL I’M GOOD AT!
( laughs )
Alice: I WILL KILL HIM.
Kirito: HEY! WAIT UP!
Chudelkin: SYSTEM CALL!
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT!
Alice: BE ON GUARD
FOR A SURPRISE ATTACK!
Kirito: YOU GOT IT!
Alice: HE WAS CHANTING
FROM HERE A MOMENT AGO.
THE 100th FLOOR IS ABOVE US,
SO PERHAPS HE FLED THERE.
Kirito: BUT HOW? I DON’T SEE
STAIRS ANYWHERE. DO YOU?
( gasps )
♪
GREAT. ANOTHER INTEGRITY KNIGHT.
Alice: NO. THAT CAN’T BE.
( Kirito gasps )
♪
( gasping )
EUGEO!
- WHAT THE HELL?
- ( Alice gasps )
BUT HOW?
IT’S TOO SOON.
Kirito: TOO SOON FOR WHAT?!
Alice: THE SYNTHESIS RITUAL.
YOUR FRIEND EUGEO
SEEMS TO HAVE
ALREADY BEEN SYNTHESIZED.
Kirito: HE IS?
NO WAY. YOU SURE?
Alice: I AM. I DO NOT KNOW
HOW IT IS POSSIBLE.
HE FOUGHT THE COMMANDER
ONLY AN HOUR AGO.
Kirito: THEN, IT’S NOT POSSIBLE.
- Alice: WAIT.
- Kirito: NOT HIM.
Alice: WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DO NOT LOSE YOUR WITS NOW.
THERE IS STILL A CHANCE
WE CAN SAVE EUGEO!
- Kirito: THERE IS?
- Alice: YES.
YOU TOLD ME SO YOURSELF.
YOU DISCOVERED A WAY TO RESTORE
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT’S MEMORIES.
THEREFORE, IT SHOULD
APPLY TO HIM AS WELL.
THE IMPORTANT THING NOW
IS YOU STAY CALM
AND GET HOLD OF YOURSELF.
Kirito: YEAH. ( grunts )
LET ME HANDLE THIS.
Alice: AS YOU WISH.
BE CAREFUL. HE IS NOT
THE PERSON YOU ONCE KNEW.
Kirito: RIGHT.
EUGEO, YOU REMEMBER WHO I AM?
I’M KIRITO.
I’M YOUR BEST FRIEND.
WE’VE BEEN TOGETHER EVER SINCE
WE LEFT RULID TWO YEARS AGO.
Eugeo: I’M SORRY.
I DON’T KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
THANK YOU, THOUGH.
Kirito: UH, FOR WHAT?
Eugeo: FOR RETURNING
MY SWORD TO ME.
Kirito: HUH?
( tone chimes )
( both gasp )
Alice: INCARNATE ARMS.
Kirito: HOW’D HE DO THAT?!
Alice: HE USED AN ANCIENT ART
TAUGHT TO INTEGRITY KNIGHTS.
IT IS NEITHER SACRED ART,
NOR PERFECT CONTROL.
IT ALLOWS ONE
TO MOVE OBJECTS AT WILL.
ONLY A HANDFUL OF KNIGHTS,
INCLUDING UNCLE,
HAVE THE SKILL
TO USE IT, THOUGH.
IT IS NOT SOMETHING
A NEWLY CREATED KNIGHT
LIKE EUGEO COULD HAVE MASTERED.
Kirito: OKAY, YOU GOT IT BACK.
SO NOW WHAT?
Eugeo: I WILL FIGHT
THE BOTH OF YOU.
IT IS WHAT MY LADY WISHES.
Kirito: OH, COME ON!
YOU’RE GONNA FIGHT ME,
YOUR FRIEND,
ALL ’CAUSE SHE TOLD YOU TO?!
THAT’S NO REASON TO FIGHT!
Eugeo: IT IS
REASON ENOUGH FOR ME.
SHE GIVES ME
EVERYTHING I EVER WANTED,
AND SHE IS ALL
I’LL EVER NEED NOW.
- Kirito: OH, GIVE ME A BREAK.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
Kirito: WHAT ABOUT ALICE?!
DO YOU REMEMBER HER?!
( Eugeo grunts )
( sighs )
I DON’T, AND I DON’T WANT TO.
I DON’T CARE
WHO EITHER OF YOU ARE.
I’VE HAD ENOUGH.
Kirito: SNAP OUT OF IT.
( boots thudding )
Eugeo: ARM YOURSELF.
I AM DONE TALKING.
♪
Kirito: YOU DON’T REMEMBER,
BUT I’M THE ONE WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO FIGHT WITH A SWORD.
KEEP THAT IN MIND,
’CAUSE I’M ABOUT TO TEACH YOU
ANOTHER LESSON.
( both exhale )
( both yell )
♪
NEXT TIME: THE 32nd KNIGHT